demandmetric.com 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy | Demand Metric

**Overview**

Welcome, and thank you for your interest in Demand Metric Research Corporation (“Demand Metric”), and our website(s), products, services and applications (the “Services”). This Privacy Policy is meant to help you understand what information we collect, why we collect it, and how you can update, manage, export, and delete your information. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you can [**_contact us_**](https://www.demandmetric.com/content/contact-us) here.

When you clicked “accept” or “agree” in connection with registering your account, we made available to you this Privacy Policy and the information handling practices described in here. This Privacy Policy only covers Demand Metric's practices regarding personal information, and not information more generally. We may use aggregated, anonymized data that we derived from your personal information before you deleted it, but not in a manner that incorporates any of your personal information or would identify you personally.

We’ll ask for your consent before using your information for a purpose that isn’t covered in this Privacy Policy. You may, of course, decline to share certain personal information with Demand Metric, in which case Demand Metric may not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionality found on the Services .

**Information Demand Metric Collects**

We collect information to provide better Services to all our users. When you’re not signed into a Demand Metric account, we store the information we collect with unique identifiers tied to the browser, application, or device you’re using. When you’re signed in, we collect information that we store with your Demand Metric account.

**Information or Content You  Provide to Us**

When you create a Demand Metric account you provide us with personal information that includes your name and a password,your email address and work/home/mobile phone number, and other personal information.

Your provision of this personal data is required for you to enter into the _**[Terms of Service](https://www.demandmetric.com/terms-of-use)**_ , a contract, with us. If you do not provide the minimum amount of personal data required to register an account, including your name and email address, you cannot use the Services, as this information is necessary for contractual reasons. Please see “European Requirements” below for further information on the bases for our processing your personal information.

We also collect the content you create, upload, or receive from others when using our Services. This includes things like messages you write, tasks, projects, comments and files uploaded.

**Information We Collect as You Use Our Services**

Your apps, browsers & devices:

We collect information about the apps, browsers, and devices you use to access our Services or open one of our HTML emails by using different types of technology, including “clear gifs” or “web beacons.” This “automatically collected” information may include Internet Protocol address (also known as “IP address”) or other device address or ID, web browser or device type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after the Services, the pages you view on the Services, and the dates and times that you visit the Services.

We use various technologies to collect and store information, including cookies, pixel tags, local storage, such as browser web storage or application data caches, databases, and server logs. Your activity:

We collect information about your activity in our Services, which may include:

  * Views and interactions with content and ads
  * People with whom you communicate or share content
  * Which assets you view or download and which projects you use
  * Cookies and web beacons

When you use the Services, we send one or more cookies – small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer. For example, we use cookies to ensure proper navigation between pages on the Services. Demand Metric may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Services. Persistent cookies can be removed. Please review your web browser’s “Help” file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. If you delete, or choose not to accept, cookies from the Services, you may not be able to utilize the features of the Services to their fullest potential.

Linked accounts:

When you link an account, you may have on a third party service (such as a third party social networking site or email provider) to your Demand Metric account, Demand Metric collects certain information stored in connection with that account that you have configured that service to make available, including your email address, provider ID, first and last name, and profile picture. By linking your accounts in this manner, you authorize Demand Metric to access and use your account on the third party service in connection with your use of the Services.

**Why Demand Metric Collects Information**

Demand Metric uses the information we collect for the following purposes:

Provide Our Services - We use your information to deliver our Services, like sending you or presenting you with, relevant content. Another example is that we use unique identifiers stored in cookies on your device to help us authenticate you as the person who should have access to your Demand Metric account.

Maintain & Improve Our Services - We also use your information to ensure our Services are working as intended, such as tracking outages or troubleshooting issues that you report to us. For example, we continuously monitor our systems to look for problems. If we find something wrong with a specific feature, reviewing activity information collected before the problem started allows us to fix things more quickly.

And we use your information to make improvements to our Services – for example, to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our Demand Metric account members and to improve the way the Services work and look.

For example, we use cookies to analyze how people interact with our Services, which can help us build better products. It may help us discover that it’s taking people too long to complete a certain task or that they have trouble finishing steps at all. We can then redesign that feature and improve the product for everyone.

Develop New Services - We use the information we collect in existing Services to help us create new features and functionality.

Provide Personalized Services - We use the information we collect to customize our Services for you, including remembering your information so that you will not have to log-in again the next time you visit the Services if you haven’t signed out. In addition, we may use the information we collect to provide personalized and relevant content, for example showing you tools and resources based on your selected “Top Priority”.

Measure Performance - We use data for analytics and measurement to understand how our Services are used. For example, we analyze data about your visits to our sites to do things like optimize product design, monitor and analyze the operation and effectiveness of the Services and related activities, and monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed. We use a variety of tools to do this, including Google Analytics. Google Analytics relies on first-party cookies, which means the cookies are set by Demand Metric. You can opt-out from Google Analytics by clicking here.

Communicate with You - We use information we collect, like your email address, to interact with you directly. For example, we may send you a notification of new resources published, or we may let you know about upcoming changes or improvements to our Services. We will also use your email address to contact you with respect to survey and webinar invitations; for administrative and customer service purposes; to address intellectual property infringement, rights of privacy, or defamation issues; or regarding things you post on the Services. Should you contact Demand Metric, we may keep a record of your request to help solve any issues you might be facing.

Share with Sponsors - Demand Metric may also send you messages related to the Services and the activities of third parties we work with. These messages may be targeted at you based on your activities on our Services, for example your interaction with a particular resource or your entry into a specific survey. You will have the ability to opt-out of receiving any such communications through links provided in the messages.

When you register for webinars, participate in surveys or download resources that are sponsored by third parties, your personal information will be provided to that particular third party along with your web activity regarding their partnered content.

Protect Demand Metric, Our Users, and the Public - We use information to help improve the safety and reliability of our Services. This includes detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, abuse, security risks, and technical issues that could harm Demand Metric, our users, or the public. For example, we collect and analyze IP addresses and cookie data to protect against automated abuse. This abuse can take many forms, such as sending spam to Demand Metric users or launching a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack. When we detect spam, malware, illegal content, and other forms of abuse on our systems in violation of our policies, we may disable your account or take other appropriate action. In certain circumstances, we may also report the violation to appropriate authorities.

**Managing and Deleting Your Information**

Managing, Reviewing, and Updating Your Information - When you’re signed into your Demand Metric account, you can always review and update information by visiting your profile.

**Exporting, Removing & Deleting Your Information**

Should you wish to export, remove or delete your personal information from Demand Metric’s services please  _ **[contact us](https://www.demandmetric.com/content/contact-us)**_ here, outlining your request, and we will complete your requested action within a 60 day period.

**Data Retention**

Information Retained Until You Remove It - For each type of data, we set retention timeframes based on the reason for its collection. As noted above, should you wish your personal data removed from our records, simply contact us and we will ensure this is done within 60 days.

Information Retained for Extended Time Periods for Limited Purposes - Sometimes business and legal requirements require us to retain certain information for specific purposes for an extended period of time. For example, when you submit a survey response, we may retain this information for a longer period of time foraggregate data evaluation/ comparison[JZ3] or for legal purposes. Reasons we might retain some data for longer periods of time include:

  * Security, fraud & abuse prevention
  * Financial record-keeping
  * Complying with legal or regulatory requirements
  * Ensuring the continuity of our services
  * Enabling Safe and Complete Deletion

**Sharing Your Information**

When You Share Your Information - Many of our Services let you share information with other people, and you have control over how you share. Any information that you voluntarily choose to include in an area of the Services accessible to other Demand Metric members, such as a public profile page, a project or in a posting, will be available to other Demand Metric members who access that content. This also applies to information you choose to make available through features that connect to third party services, if applicable.

Also, if you communicate directly with another Demand Metric member, any information that you voluntarily choose to include in such a communication with other Demand Metric members will be available to such other members. Once you make your information available in any of these ways, it could be collected and used by the recipients without restriction. We urge Demand Metric members to exercise common sense, prudence and good judgment about what information to make available to others through the Services.

**When Demand Metric Shares Your Information**

For external processing - We provide personal information to our affiliates and other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. These third parties may have access to or process your personal information as a result of performing the services they were engaged to perform.

  * For legal reasons - We will share personal information outside of Demand Metric if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:
  * Meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request.
  * Enforce our Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations, and take precautions against liability.
  * Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, abuse, security, or technical issues.
  * Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Demand Metric or our affiliates, our users, or the public as required or permitted by law.
  * Protect the security or integrity of the Services and to protect or enforce third party rights.
  * If Demand Metric is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets, we’ll continue to ensure the confidentiality of your personal information and give affected users notice before personal information is transferred or becomes subject to a different privacy policy.
  * To Fulfill Partnership Contracts - As noted above, when you register for webinars, participate in surveys or download resources that are sponsored by third parties, your personal information will be provided to that particular third party along with your web activity regarding their partnered content. Agreeing to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service is your consent to this sharing of your personal information.

**Our Commitment to Data Security**

Demand Metric uses a variety of physical, managerial, and technical safeguards designed to improve the security of our systems and your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Demand Metric, nor can we guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. You transfer your information to Demand Metric at your own risk. If Demand Metric learns of a security breach, we will notify you in accordance with applicable law.

**Third Party Websites**

The Services contain links to websites and services provided by third parties. Any personal information you provide on third party sites or services is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party’s policies governing privacy and security. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of third party sites or services to which links are displayed on the Services. We encourage you to learn about third parties’ privacy and security policies before providing them with personal information.

**Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of children is especially important. For that reason, Demand Metric does not knowingly collect or maintain personal information from persons under 13 years old, and no part of the Services is directed to persons under 13. IF YOU ARE UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE, PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE SERVICES AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER.

If Demand Metric learns that personal information of children under 13 years old has been collected on the Services without verifiable parental consent, then Demand Metric will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained a user account on the Services, then you may alert Demand Metric at Contact Usand request that Demand Metric delete that child’s personal information from its systems. If you are between the ages of 13 and 18 years old, you may not use the Services until Demand Metric has received verifiable parental consent for your use of the Services. 

**Compliance & Cooperation with Regulators**

We regularly review this Privacy Policy and make sure that we process your information in ways that comply with it.

**Data Transfers**

Your information may be processed on servers located outside of the country where you live. Data protection laws vary among countries, with some providing more protection than others. Regardless of where your information is processed, we apply the same protections described in this policy. 

When we receive formal written complaints, we respond by contacting the person who made the complaint. We work with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of your data that we cannot resolve with you directly.

**European Requirements**

If European Union (EU) data protection law applies to the processing of your information, you can exercise your right to request access to, update, remove, and restrict the processing of your information. You also have the right to object to the processing of your information or export your information to another service. Please reach out to use via our Contact Uspage and advise us that you would like to exercise these rights.

We process your information for the purposes described in this policy, based on the following legal grounds:

With your consent - By accepting our Terms of Service and our Privacy Policy, which was presented to you at the time of your registration, you have provided Demand Metric with your consent to use your personal information as described in this policy.  We ask for your agreement to process your information for specific purposes and you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. If you withdraw your consent this may impact your ability to receive some of Demand Metric services. To withdraw your consent simply **_[contact us](https://www.demandmetric.com/content/contact-us)_**.

  * When we’re pursuing legitimate interests - We process your information for our legitimate interests while applying appropriate safeguards that protect your privacy. This means that we process your information for things like:
  * Providing, maintaining, and improving our Services to meet the needs of our users
  * Developing new products and features that are useful for our users
  * Understanding how people use our Services to ensure and improve the performance of our Services
  * Customizing our Services to provide you with a better user experience
  * Marketing to inform users about our Services
  * Detecting, preventing, or otherwise addressing fraud, abuse, security, or technical issues with our Services
  * Protecting against harm to the rights, property or safety of Demand Metric, our users, or the public as required or permitted by law
  * Performing research that improves our Services for our users and benefits the public
  * Fulfilling obligations to our research partners
  * Enforcing legal claims, including investigation of potential violations of our Terms of Service
  * When we’re providing a service
  * We process your data to provide a service you’ve asked for under a contract. For example, we process your information in connection with the projects you use or the surveys in which you participate.
  * When we’re complying with legal obligations - We’ll process your data when we have a legal obligation to do so, for example, if we’re responding to legal process or an enforceable governmental request.

**Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Note that our amended Privacy Policy will become effective on a going-forward basis as stated in the Terms, except that (i) unless you agree otherwise, we will use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when we received that information and (ii) if you do not agree with any changes to the Privacy Policy, you must terminate your Demand Metric membership and cease use of the Services.Your continued use of the Services after a revised Privacy Policy has become effective indicates that you have read, understood and agreed to the current version of the Privacy Policy.

**Demand Metric Contact Information**

Please contact Demand Metric with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, your personal information, our use and disclosure practices, or your consent choices through our [**_contact us_**](https://www.demandmetric.com/content/contact-us) form.
